



# **Dave Hearne**

# Senior User Experience Developer/Designer CDU



dhearne@tssg.org



051 302964

# **PROFILE**

Dave is a highly experienced designer and developer with 10+ years working in the industry.

Dave has always focused on Usability and Accessibility of web and mobile applications. Dave has a passion for User Experience as he feels it is the most important aspect of any product.

In 2018 Dave joined TSSG as senior UX developer/designer. Dave's main roles and responsibilities include front end design & development of mobile and web based applications. Dave also focuses creating user personas, empathy maps, wireframes & prototypes based on correlated data from workshops & testing.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Senior UX Designer / Developer

June 2018 - Present

#### **TSSG**

Responsible for a multitude of areas including UX/UI design, design & development for mobile and web applications. Duties include technical diagrams, wireframes, website layout and designs, presentations, Custom Website creation and maintenance along with working directly with clients and the CDU team to take ideas from concept to a completed project.

#### **Lead Front End Developer**

April 2015 - June 2018

#### **Threefold Systems**

At Threefold, my duties went beyond development. I focused mainly on UX strategy, UI design and training junior developers. I work on everything, from designing and building components for large web apps to UX reviews, new websites and mobile applications for Agora affiliates across the globe.

#### Senior Web Designer & Developer

April 2015 - June 2018

#### **Passion for Creative**

Here my duties included designing and developing websites for a variety of clients across the globe, from single page websites in Ireland to large eCommerce systems in the UK and Australia.

ww.tssg.org | dhearne@tssg.org | +353(0)51 302964

### **EDUCATION**

#### **Masters in Interactive Media**

University College Cork

2007 - 2009

During this intensive course I studied every aspect of web design and development with a huge focus on User Experience, Usability and the importance of online presence.

**Grade:** First Class honours

#### **BSc (Hons) in Multimedia Applications Development**

Waterford Institute of Technology

2010-2014

This is where my love of design and development began. During my 4 years in WIT I learned many web languages and scripting languages. I also focused a lot on front end design and development.

**Grade:** Second Class honours

# **SKILLS**

**User Experience** including: Client workshops, User-story development, Persona Development, Market Research & Competitor Analysis, Wire framing, Low and High Fidelity Prototyping (inVision), , information architecture design , Interaction Design.

**Visual Design** including: UI Design for Web-platforms/IOS/Android Apps, digital & print design (Adobe Creative Suite, Sketch, Zeplin).

**Web Development**: Expert Knowledge of CSS, HTML and JavaScript including JS libraries including Angular. Also knowledge of backend development including PHP, NodeJS, MySQL, Mongo DB

www.tssg.org | dhearne@tssg.org | +353(0)51 302964